<entry>
  <title>The Horrible Moment when Everything Works</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://rsdy.github.com/posts/building_infrastructure.html"/>
  <id>http://rsdy.github.com/posts/building_infrastructure.html</id>
  <updated>2012-09-29T00:09:36Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There hasn't been an update on the <a href="http://indiegogo.com/kitchensync">KitchenSync</a> project site for some time, and this is because I started the crowdfunding campaign just after moving to the UK, and needed to bootstrap my own little network infrastructure in my flat. I did not have the time, nor the possibility to work on the Raspberry Pi software, because I just didn't have the hardware setup that was necessary.</p>
                                <p>This has changed. I bought myself a router, the USB mains charger with a UK plug, and finally set it all up.</p>
                                <p>I wasn't particularly interested in the stock firmware that came with the router, so right after unpacking, I flashed DD-WRT on it. Sadly, I found out only after I had received the box that it is not supported by OpenWRT, so I had to stick with the other popular WRT distribution.</p>
                                <p>There are actually many reasons one might want to eliminate the stock firmware from their home router. Not only do you get the chance to opt out some <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/7/2/3131738/cisco-linksys-router-update-connect-cloud">weird corporate cloud</a>, it also extends the functionality. My ISP requires me to log in on a captive portal after 30 minutes of inactivity, but fortunately they didn't put much effort into hardening their login page. Thus, a simple cron one-liner on the router did the trick, which would have been impossible with the stock firmware.</p>
                                <p>I have also put my laptop dock into good use after all. When I leave home, I just undock my machine, and pop it in my bag. With a huge battery, I can go all day without a charger, so that's fine. If the machine rests on the dock, it just uses the wired connection with the router, and my USB hard drives spin up.</p>
                                <p>The Raspberry Pi, my soon-to-be KitchenSync, is placed just beside the router. Sadly, I don't yet have the fancy case for it, but as soon as it arrives, I'll start posting pictures. Luckily, I have UTP cables in different colours for all my wired devices, so my desk doesn't look like a pile of boring gadgets (firstly, because it isn't).</p>
                                <p>Why is this even exciting? Because this is the first time I'm in full control over the network setup at home, and just because I love it when suddenly everything starts to work. Even better, my phone, the Raspberry Pi, the router, and my laptop are all powered by some sort of Linux. I actually realised this after having set up everything, but I think it's cool anyway.</p>
                                <p>In some twisted sense, however, I'm also sad. This means that the infrastructure works as it should, and I don't have any ideas on improving it. Apart from some proper VPN setup. And an Arduino temperature sensor. And KitchenSync.</p>]]></content>
</entry>
