<entry>
  <title>The Humbleness of the Dish</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://rsdy.github.com/posts/the_humbleness_of_the_dish.html"/>
  <id>http://rsdy.github.com/posts/the_humbleness_of_the_dish.html</id>
  <updated>2012-09-17T13:03:59Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've discovered today a fabulous <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/slideshow/2012/09/12/dining/20120912-SPANISH.html">picture-illustrated recipe</a> for the perfect fried eggs, and after trying out myself, I started thinking about how the world-class chefs are <a href="http://youtu.be/dU_B3QNu_Ks">obsessed</a> with the <a href="http://youtu.be/57afEWn-QDg">idea</a> of <a href="http://youtu.be/AgHgbn_sVUw">perfectly prepared eggs</a>.</p>
                                <p>The few words that really caught my eye in the description of José Andrés's technique were &quot;the humbleness of the dish&quot;. I think all of the other videos mention that when you want to test whether a chef is indeed worthy, you have them make something out of a handful of eggs.</p>
                                <p>Programmers have something similar to the egg-test, called <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2007/02/why-cant-programmers-program.html">FizzBuzz</a>. I know a couple of companies who make use of the FizzBuzz test with each of their applicants, just to determine if he or she can program at all, although I would not go as far as drawing a conclusion about their skills.</p>
                                <p>More interestingly, the humbleness of eggs is what I haven't realised before. Eggs are abundant, they're cheap, and really easy to prepare, yet, depending on how you do it, you will get very different results. As I love to experiment with food, I have some routine in preparing eggs in a couple of ways, and for a quick dinner I usually choose one that suits my mood, or just give it some thought, and try something new. If it is any good, I'll have plenty of times to perfect the preparation, starting with the next day, for example.</p>
                                <p>This is exactly why I love the UNIX command line tools. They are really versatile, and the shell, in particular, is often under-estimated by even experienced geeks. The fact, that something scales from standard day-to-day tasks, such as file manipulation, to more complex things like a blog engine, is fascinating.</p>
                                <p>Keeping the KISS principle of software development will help you create better software, very much like eggs make a perfect dinner if you spice them up a bit so that they make a difference. I've seen many people use loads of Python code just to accomplish what could have been done in two lines of shell.</p>
                                <p>It's all about knowing the simple ingredients you have at hand, and realise when they're enough for a dinner. If you are really hungry, you will need to add some more vegetables, fish, meat, or whatever floats your boat, but don't waste your energy preparing a big meal, when some eggs will suffice, that just makes you even more hungry.</p>]]></content>
</entry>
